Golden State Mutual Life Insurance Company records LSC.1434
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Awards and Memorabilia, 1938, 1941, 1945-1966, 1968, 1970, 1974, 1979-1980, 1989, 1991, undated
  - Awards, 1938, 1941, 1945-1966, 1968, 1970, 1974, 1979-1980, 1989, 1991, undated (Box 297, Box 298, Box 299, Box 300)
    Box 297: Materials include National Insurance Association certificates for outstanding public relations tools, George A. Beavers, Jr.'s certificate of appointment to the Housing Authority of the City of Los Angeles signed by Mayor Fletcher Bowron, Life Insurance Advertisers Association Awards of Excellence, Community Health Award, Community Chest Awards, Los Angeles County Heart Association Certificate of Appreciation, Handicapped Placement Center of Los Angeles Certificate of Appreciation for Outstanding Service to the Handicapped, Mount Logan Grand Lodge Award of Merit to Norman O. Houston, Our Authors Study Club Certificate of Merit, United Crusade 3rd Award plate, Los Angeles City Council Resolution in honor of GSM's 34th Anniversary signed by all council members including Edward R. Roybal, Golden Pen Award to Benjamin E. Mays, GSM citation of honor for outstanding achievements and representation of the citizens of Los Angeles to world champion pugilist Henry Armstrong, City of Los Angeles and Private Industry Council Outstanding Job Training Partnership Act Award signed by Mayor Tom Bradley and a file of GSM award specimens (1938, 1941, 1945-1966, 1979-1980, 1991, undated).
    Box 298: Materials include Norman O. Houston's University of California Regents Bachelor of Science Degree plaque (June 17, 1948).
    Box 299: Materials include a George A. Beavers, Jr. appreciation plaque signed by the Home Office employees and a Seasons Greetings to George A. Beavers, Jr. plaque signed by his Home Office colleagues (October 28, 1966, 1970).
    Box 300: Materials include Norman O. Houston's National Recreation and Parks Association Board of Trustees appointment certificate, Los Angeles City Council Resolution of commendation to George A. Beavers, Jr. for his outstanding service to the community, Norman O. Houston's Honorary Citizen of Dallas, Texas certificate and Senator Diane E. Watson's California State Senate Rule Committee Resolution of congratulations and commendation to GSM on its 64th Anniversary (1968, 1974, 1989).
  - Memorabilia, 1949-1958, 1961, 1971, 1977, 1983, 1985, 1986, 2000, 2001 (Box 301, Box 302, Box 303, Box 304, Box 305, Box 306, Box 307)
    Box 301: The Home Office guest register includes signatures and addresses of visitors such as J.H. Jackson, Hale Woodruff, Booker T. Washington III, Ethel Ray Nance, Mrs. Marion Jones and Paul Robeson (1950-1958).
    Box 302: Materials include the engraved trowel from the Home Office cornerstone laying dedication on August 23, 1949, the scissors used for the Home Office ribbon cutting ceremony, Home Office open house souvenirs such as matchbooks, sewing kits and hand lotion pillows, Honor Pin samples, GSM address books, key chains, first aid kits, tie pins, 75th Anniversary stickers, buttons, Golden Rule marbles, a GSM analog clock, bottle opener, Directors broach, bracelet, Ivan J. Houston signature stamps, keychain and paperweight and pins for the following: Roundtable Member, Millionaire Leaders Roundtable, Executive's Club, President's Club, Chairman's Club and the NIA.
    Box 303: Materials include GSM "Peace of Mind and Security" wooden pencil holders, "Take the Strain Off Your Insurance Needs" plastic strainers, address labels, vinyl briefcases, "We're Creating Millionaires" golden bumper stickers, "100% Satisfaction is the Rule" rulers, GSM magnifying ruler, "An Extra Inch of Protection" ruler, check holders and a pocket-sized vinyl covered address book.
    Box 304: Materials include GSM neck ties, book bags, a banner, a baseball cap, a Loomis Armored Car Service cash deposit bag for the Bank of America on 15th and Broadway and church fans with images of the following: Mahalia Jackson, The Last Supper, Juneteenth Black History Month freedom collage, Black National Anthem lyrics, GSM starburst logo and "Together Again" with Martin Luther King, Jr. sitting in front of the Holy Bible and a portrait of his mother.
    Box 305: Materials include the following posters: John Fitzgerald Kennedy Inaugural Address sent to GSM from the Office of Augustus F. Hawkins, Famous Black American Entertainers Part I and II, 2nd World Black and African Festival of Arts and Culture, Martin Luther King, Jr. Holiday Legislation Remarks of President Ronald Reagan and Mrs. Coretta King, Crispus Attucks, Martin Luther King, Jr. "I Have A Dream" designed by Avery Clayton, Black Art: An International Quarterly and MLK January 15.
    Box 306: Seven photo collages include images of George A. Beavers, Jr. at Dodger Stadium, the GSM Art Collection and employees at the Home Office, aboard the Queen Mary, at conferences and celebratory dinners. Panorama photograph of NNIA Convention 30th Annual Session, July 19, 1950.
    Box 307: Two "Founders Month" posters include images of George A. Beavers, Jr., William Nickerson, Jr. and Norman O. Houston above the following words: "They sowed the seed; ours the job to reap the harvest. Dedicated to these three men who caused Golden State Mutual Life Insurance Company to come into being, thereby creating a legacy for untold numbers of their fellow men."